# **Arsen Arakelyan**

## **Backend Software Engineer**

Current location: **Berlin, Germany**<u>Telegram Gmail LinkedIn GitHub</u>

#### **ABOUT ME**

As a Backend Engineer with 3+ years of experience in Software Engineering. I have experience working primarily with Node.js as well as Cloud Solutions and worked in various sectors like healthcare, education, e-commerce, and infrastructure automation (IDP), so I can adapt to different domains.

#### **SKILLS**

**Languages:** JavaScript, TypeScript

Technologies: Node.js (Express.js, Nest.js) GraphQL (Apollo), RabbitMQ, Redis, Stripe

Databases: PostgreSQL, TypeORM, Knex.js, MongoDB, Mongoose

**DevOps:** Linux, Docker, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, GitHub, GitLab, AWS (EC2, S3, Lambda,

AWS SAM, EKS), Terraform, Ansible

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Backend Engineer, Kepler Technologies** | Contractor

11.2022 - 02.2023

**Project description:** <u>meMR</u> **Health** is a fully **automated AI record retrieval platform** that auto-categorizes & transforms records into high-yield data.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Developed a doctor-specific admin panel to replace the Zoho dashboard.
- Migrated from Firebase to AWS Cognito for streamlined services.
- Boosted development and testing efficiency through CI process implementation.
- Created and optimized indexes for PostgreSQL
- Optimized dynamic pdf file generation from 80 sec to 15 sec.

**Tech Stack**: TypeScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Docker, GitLab, AWS (Cognito, EC2, IAM, OpenSearch)

**Software Engineer, EPAM Systems** | Full Time

*12.2021 – 09.2022* 

**Project description: Internal Developer Platform** for automating infrastructure processes.

#### Responsibilities:

- Worked on an Internal Developer Platform for automating infrastructure processes and environment setup which reduced onboarding time by 2.6x!
- Configured CI/CD processes, including ESLint, Prettier, GitHub Webhooks/Actions, and ArgoCD for Kubernetes.
- Optimized the MongoDB Models for better performance.
- Used Xstate.js for dynamic task management within a state machine.
- As a Key Developer I was Responsible for interviewing and onboarding our new team members, and also have experience with interviewing Engineers

#### to external who wanted to join the company.

**Tech Stack**: TypeScript, Node.js, MongoDB, Jest, XState.js, Docker, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, SonarQube, AWS (SAM, Lambda, API Gateway, IAM), Hashicorp (Vault, Terraform)

Non-project activities: Mentored 3 mentees in the Global Node.js Mentorship Program. Conducted code reviews to ensure quality and industry standards. Organized Q&A sessions and paired programming for effective learning.

### JavaScript Engineer, MobiDev | Full Time

05.2021 - 12.2021

**Project description:** Created new features and fixed bugs from the last developers, for <u>STEERus</u> which is specified in soft skills.

### Responsibilities:

- Developed GraphQL schemas and services for user requests.
- Implemented features for uploading images and videos to AWS S3 for tutors.
- Developed real-time streaming lessons functionality using Mux.
- Implemented the **whole checkout and billing feature with Stripe** for ordering the courses.
- Optimized database queries, cause used the knex.js

**Tech Stack**: TypeScript, Node.js, GraphQL, AWS (RDS, EC2), PostgreSQL, SendGrid, Stripe, Mux, Ngrok, Docker

**Project description:** <u>AVELYN</u> is an innovative online platform that bridges the gap between wine producers and enthusiasts.

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Developed the whole search functionality for users to find wines by name or brand back/front sides.
- Implemented a filtering and sorting functionality for wines based on region, grape, and style.
- Implemented the whole checkout and billing feature with Stripe for ordering wines.

**Tech Stack**: TypeScript, Node.js, Nest.js, React, Redux, AWS (RDS, EC2), PostgreSQL, Docker, Stripe

## Node.js Engineer, Chi Software | Full time

07.2020 - 05.2021

Project description: Break down the monolith with Python and Django to microservices with Node.js and Typescript, for better performance for Chewy. Responsibilities:

- Rewrote 2 services for dynamic price calculation and logistic processes from 8 microservices.
- Managed 5 service chains flow of queues for efficient data flow.
- Optimized database queries for improving ORM performance.

**Tech Stack**: TypeScript, Node.js, AWS (RDS, EC2, SNS, SQS), PostgreSQL, RabbitMQ, Docker

## **EDUCATION**

## Kharkiv National University of Economics (KNUE)

09.2014 - 12.2019

Management of financial risks of the enterprise. Master's degree